<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Italo Amaya</title>
    <link>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Italo Amaya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://italoamaya.me/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sweet_potato_dessert</title>
      <link>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_dessert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_dessert/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Sweet potato mandarins Instructions Chop the sweet potato into slices as thick as your finger. Slice the mandarin. Add the sweet potato to a container for the oven. Squeeze the mandarin into the sweet potato. Start the oven in high heat and once the oven is hot lower it down. If they look dry squeeze more juice. Bonus You can also add aluminum foil on top once the sweet potato is crisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/teriyaki_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/teriyaki_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Soy sauce Mirin sauce Sake Sugar Instructions Add equal parts of Soy sauce, Mirin and Sake. Stir and then add half part sugar. Extras You can also add garlic and onions by grating them in any cheese grater. These add a bit of a kick to the sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup Brownie</title>
      <link>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/cup_brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://italoamaya.me/recipes/cup_brownie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 and 1/2 tbsp butter 30g cocoa 2 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp milk 4 tbsp all purpose flour 1/4 tsp baking powder pinch salt Instructions add butter to cup and place into microwave until its melted tilt the cup to get the sides of the cup with butter add the flour, cocoa, sugar and baking powder. mix and then add the milk place in the microwave again checking constantly </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
