<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italo Amaya</title>
    <link>//italoamaya.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Italo Amaya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//italoamaya.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning OpenGl - Creating a Window</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/learning_opengl-creating_a_window/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/learning_opengl-creating_a_window/</guid>
      <description>GLFW This is a library that allows us to facilitate the process of creating a window defining the context to of opengl and handle the user input.
Gl instead of GLAD This is a library that&amp;rsquo;s has the purpose of being the opengl function pointer loader.
Initialize glfw This is how we are initializing glfw to create the opengl context.
// glfw: initialize and configure // ------------------------------ let mut glfw = glfw::init(glfw::FAIL_ON_ERRORS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning OpenGl</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/learning_opengl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/learning_opengl/</guid>
      <description>What resources I am using At the moment I am starting with Learn_OpenGl_rust and am planing on using this resource for this entire learning process.
Introduction As I understand the opengl library started out with the immediate mode. This mode was easy to use and made the idea of drawing graphics way easier. But it was inefficient, which resulted in opengl developing the core-profile mode which is what is being used now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding_cowsay_to_ssh</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/adding_cowsay_to_ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/adding_cowsay_to_ssh/</guid>
      <description>Install Packages sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade sudo apt install cowsay fortune Create the RC The following Bash commands will be run everytime you log in to ssh. The commands need to be added to ~/.ssh/rc.
#!/bin/bash clear echo &amp;#34;&amp;#34; fortune | cowsay -cowsay -f $(ls /usr/share/cowsay/cows/ | shuf -n 1) echo &amp;#34;$(uptime)&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;&amp;#34; Source : original post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pepper Veggie Sauce</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/pepper_veggie_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/pepper_veggie_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients All the types of Bell peppers you can find Jalapeños Onion Garlic Olive oil Lemons Instructions In a baking tray add the whole garlic with the top chopped. add olive oil to the garlic. add the rest of the veggies chopped in chunks so they get cooked. Cook for 35-40 min. Remove the cloves from the whole garlic. move the veggies to a blender. Add lemon juice While mixing them use olive oil to emulsify the mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulled Pork (Instant Pot)</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/pulled_pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/pulled_pork/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Pork Shoulder ~1kg
Chili Powder (Maybe paprica) 4 tbsp
Salt 1 tbsp
Cumin 2 tsp
Oregano
Onion Powder 1 tsp
Olive oil
Garlic Powder 1 tsp
Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the measurements they are approximates use your own and experiment with flavor
Instructions Seasoning the pork Mix all the spices into a bowl and mix them. Dry the pork shoulder. With your hands add Olive oil to the meat so the spices stick to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Gnocchi</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Sweet Potato Flour Instructions Pierce the sweet potato with a fork. Bake them in the oven. Take the skin out. make mashed sweet potato. Add salt. Add flour and mix with your hands until its a dough. Take the dough and make it a ball Cut the ball into 4 and make for each a long snake Then cut the snake into the gnocchi source: https://www.youtube.com/shorts/udaSYLYGaaA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Sauce For Pasta</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/white_sauce_for_pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/white_sauce_for_pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Milk Flour Butter Mushrooms Instructions Sauce Melt the butter (~80g) on a pot at low heat. add 2 spoons of flour add 400ml of milk progressively to the pot Mushrooms Cut the mushrooms into slices. Cook the slices in a pan (optional, use butter). Add Salt and pepper to the mushrooms. Transfer the mushrooms to the pot with the white sauce. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causa</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/causa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/causa/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Potato Tomato Mayo Hard boiled egg Yellow chili pepper Instructions Boil potato peal the potato Press through a potato press to make mashed potato Press the potato while hot Make Yellow chili pepper paste Mix the paste and the mashed potato to make the dough #+begin_alert-heading Warning #+end-heading This is a work in progress</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peruvian Chaufa</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/peruvian_chaufa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/peruvian_chaufa/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Rice Sesame oil Garlic (1 clove) Red Pepper (cubes) Collar (Strips) Broccoli Chinese bean Protein (Chicken, Pork, Beef) (Sliced small) (Fry on sesame oil and soy) Soy sauce Egg Kion Chinese onion Instructions Preparation Prepare a Clove of Garlic Make a scrambled egg tortilla and do some slices Prepare broccoli branches Cut the collar into strips Cut Pepper into cubes Cut the Kion as small Rice Start with Sesame oil Add 1/2 of a clove of garlic A nail of kion Rest of ingredients Start with Sesame oil Add the protein Add Broccoli Add Collar Add Chinese bean Add the rest Mix Add the Pan with the protein and ingredients into the Rice cooker or pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting_up_shh</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_shh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_shh/</guid>
      <description>What is SSH This is the main protocol for communicating with your server so make sure is properly set up. For me the most important aspect to add is SSH-keys. This are like files in your system that are used to authenticate with the server. This is used instead of a password.
How to configure SSH Config File The following config are some of my definitive.
This is in /etc/ssh/sshd_config</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting_up_ssl__nginx</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_ssl__nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_ssl__nginx/</guid>
      <description>What is ssl? This step enables the visitor to come to the website on a secure connection.
Install certbot apt install python3-certbot-nginx Run the cerbot installation It will ask for which domain to enable the https. Domain is required Go throug the installation and check for the https in your browser
certbot --nginx Automatic certificate renewal crontab -e and add this to the end
0 0 1 * * certbot --nginx renew </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting_up_nginx</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_nginx/</guid>
      <description>Nginx Install This is the web server that will handle all http/s connections.
sudo apt install nginx Configuration Decide on a name for the nginx configuration and create a new config for nginx. In case you are not familiar with nginx the configurations of the web server go inside /etc/nginx/sites-available/. The sites available directory is used to store the configurations. To enable the configurations you can symlink then to the /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/ directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting_up_ssl_nginx</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_ssl_nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_ssl_nginx/</guid>
      <description>What is ssl? This step enables the visitor to come to the website on a secure connection.
Install certbot apt install python3-certbot-nginx Run the cerbot installation It will ask for which domain to enable the https. Domain is required Go throug the installation and check for the https in your browser
certbot --nginx Automatic certificate renewal crontab -e and add this to the end
0 0 1 * * certbot --nginx renew </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet_potato_dessert</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_dessert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/sweet_potato_dessert/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Sweet potato mandarins Instructions Chop the sweet potato into slices as thick as your finger. Slice the mandarin. Add the sweet potato to a container for the oven. Squeeze the mandarin into the sweet potato. Start the oven in high heat and once the oven is hot lower it down. If they look dry squeeze more juice. Bonus You can also add aluminum foil on top once the sweet potato is crisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with reverse engineering</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/starting_with_reverse_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/starting_with_reverse_engineering/</guid>
      <description>What tools I use I started out with ghidra and found that rather slow and slugish. I am a big emacs and vim user so efficiency is a must. Luckily I knew about radare2. Radare2 is a command line tool to disassemble and reverse binaries plus much much more. I found that radare was easier to use for small binaries like the ones from crackmes.
Resources In my opinion LiveOverflow playlist on binary exploitation is amazing and as a bigginer is a great place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/teriyaki_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/teriyaki_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Soy sauce Mirin sauce Sake Sugar Instructions Add equal parts of Soy sauce, Mirin and Sake. Stir and then add half part sugar. Extras You can also add garlic and onions by grating them in any cheese grater. These add a bit of a kick to the sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting_up_hugo</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/setting_up_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Now that I have a server I started to play around with the site generation of hugo. It can be a bit complicated If you are using emacs and org mode like me so I will divide this explanation in to three parts: Ox-Hugo (You can skip this if you are using only md), Content Organization and Configurations.
Set up hugo Download hugo You are going to want to install hugo in your personal machine apart from your server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating this site</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/posts/creating_this_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/posts/creating_this_site/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer Most of the information here is taken from the tutorial in Land Chad check them out!
Introduction and process. This is the process I went through while making this same website. At first I tried to make a basic html and css website but my design skills where not enough. I also considered using Hugo because I use org mode almost daily and there is a package called ox-hugo, which makes transformation of the org-mode syntax into the markdown for hugo simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup Brownie</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/recipes/cup_brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/recipes/cup_brownie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 and 1/2 tbsp butter 30g cocoa 2 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp milk 4 tbsp all purpose flour 1/4 tsp baking powder pinch salt Instructions add butter to cup and place into microwave until its melted tilt the cup to get the sides of the cup with butter add the flour, cocoa, sugar and baking powder. mix and then add the milk place in the microwave again checking constantly </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//italoamaya.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//italoamaya.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Current Projects These are the current projects I am working on
About Me I am currently studying Computer Science. Currently my Favorite programming language is rust and have been building some projects with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
